<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSQuery on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/tags/osquery/</link><description>Recent content in OSQuery on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.velociraptor.app/tags/osquery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating from OSQuery to Velociraptor</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-02-03-migrating-from-osquery-to-velociraptor-d4143799953f/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-02-03-migrating-from-osquery-to-velociraptor-d4143799953f/</guid><description>Tips for the journey Photo by &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://unsplash.com/@heidifin?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Heidi Fin&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; on &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Unsplash&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Photo by Heidi Fin on Unsplash
OSQuery has been around for a while now, and was actually the initial inspiration for Velociraptor. Back in the day, it became clear to me that the way to provide unprecedented flexibility for endpoint visibility was to have a flexible and powerful query language. OSQuery was historically a proof that a powerful query language was the way forward, and VQL was designed to improve on OSQuery and push the state of the art.</description></item><item><title>Velociraptor and OSQuery</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2020/2020-12-13-velociraptor-and-osquery-2a4306dd23c/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2020/2020-12-13-velociraptor-and-osquery-2a4306dd23c/</guid><description>One of our favorite tools for endpoint visibility is OSQuery. OSQuery has really transformed the state of endpoint visibility and DFIR by allowing analysts to flexibly issue queries to introspect endpoint state, just like a database. This flexibility has always been the inspiration for Velociraptor, and the development of the Velociraptor Query Language (VQL) followed the footsteps of OSQuery to provide a powerful and flexible query language.
However, while OSQuery provides a query engine with many plugins exposing machine state, it is not typically enough on its own.</description></item></channel></rss>