<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.velociraptor.app/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Closer Look at the Winning Entry in the 2021 Velociraptor Contributor Competition</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-10-22-a-closer-look-at-the-winning-entry-in-the-2021-velociraptor-contributor-competition-575c387610af/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-10-22-a-closer-look-at-the-winning-entry-in-the-2021-velociraptor-contributor-competition-575c387610af/</guid><description>On Friday October 9 the Velociraptor team crowned the grand prize winner in our 2021 Contributor Competition — unanimously won by Justin Welgemoed. His entry, “File Type Detection and Client-Server-Client Workflows” absolutely WOWed the judges. Want to learn more about Justin’s submission and how it takes Velociraptor to the next level? Read below for a deep dive into his work.
2021 Velociraptor Contributor Competition Entry: File Type Detection and Client-Server-Client Workflows Currently most Velociraptor artifacts are written in such a way that they are self-contained and are therefore mostly useful in a standalone manner.</description></item><item><title>The 2021 Contributor Contest</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-10-08-contributor-contest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/blog/2021/2021-10-08-contributor-contest/</guid><description>The 2021 Velociraptor Contributor Competition has drawn to a close and this year we have received 6 excellent submissions. Each submission pushes the state of the art in DFIR and enhances Velociraptor&amp;rsquo;s capabilities. Without our wonderful Community an open source project such as Velociraptor would not be nearly as capable.
And the winners are&amp;hellip; We are thrilled to announce the winners of the Competition! Each of these submissions separated itself from the pack by earning the top combined ratings in five key selection criteria:</description></item></channel></rss>