<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Knowledge Base on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</title><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/</link><description>Recent content in Knowledge Base on Velociraptor - Digging deeper!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/debugging_clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/debugging_clients/</guid><description>How do I debug the client while it is running? Sometimes we collect artifacts from clients but for some reason things seem to take longer than expected. Velociraptor has mechanisms to gain visibility into how clients behave and what queries are running.
Query logs The first port of call is viewing the query logs in the logs tab of the relevant collection.
Viewing the query logs As the query is running, it will emit a message to let us know that it is waiting for rows.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/deploying_in_agentless_mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/deploying_in_agentless_mode/</guid><description>How do I deploy the client as agentless (without install)? Sometimes we need to deploy Velociraptor in an IR and can not install it permanently as a service.
It is possible to deploy the client using Group Policy by using Scheduled task feature to cause domain connected machines to run the client.
The first step is to place the client and the generated client.config.yaml on a public read only windows share.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.velociraptor.app/knowledge_base/tips/template/</guid><description>This is a knowledge base template. Please rename the file above prior to preparing a pull request. This file is in markdown format.
This is the title of the article It should be in the form of a question or task - for example: How do I search for malicious downloaded files? (The website will use the first heading as the searchable title.)
The first paragraph after the title should be a short description of the kb article.</description></item></channel></rss>